you got a chance to to play considerable
snaps start in in 2023 in in Dallas. I'm
just curious how much uh of familiarity
do you have with with that will
linebacker spot and and just what have
you been told about the opportunity to
kind of you know see a significant role
here in Detroit's defense and how
excited are you for that opportunity?
>> Uh first and foremost got to give all
praise and glory to God um for the
opportunity to be here. Um without God,
I wouldn't be in the position that I'm
in today. And um it's a surreal moment,
you know, obviously going into year
five. Um a lot of football that I've
played a good bit of ball. I know I have
a lot of football left from uh to learn,
you know, I'm just excited for the
opportunity. Um to answer your question
about the wheel job, bro, football is
ball. Like ball is ball at the end of
the day. you know, you um you know,
trust your preparation, listen to the
coaches, trust your coach's preparation,
and go out there and do it. So, I don't
look at it like Mike Spot, Will, Sam. I
don't look at it like that. I look at it
like football is football. The more you
can do, the better, and you know, the
better the better you do, you know, the
more you play.
>> Thank you.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Justin,
>> welcome to Detroit. Um I'm I'm curious.
uh you overlap with Shep at LSU.
Obviously, he was, you know, uh really
important with that program, but he had
the year there where he was in more of a
I don't know if we'll call it a
counseling or mentorship role. And I'm
just wondering what kind of relationship
you you forged with him uh during that
time and what kind of relationship at
all you've you've maintained with him
over the years.
>> Oh, yeah. You know, uh purple and gold,
you know, through and through,
obviously, you know, LSU. Um, but I've
been knowing Shup since, uh, always knew
about Shep, you know, obviously like
playing at LSU after him, you know,
being one of the best linebackers to
come through LSU. Um and we were able to
overlap each other in 2020 and um him
being more on the player development
side, you know, he still was the he
played ball in the league already, you
know, so he was a guy that would give us
coaching points, you know, like he
wasn't the linebacker coach, but he
still went outside of his job, which
helping the linebackers um you know,
whatever way that he could, you know,
and I'm just excited for the
opportunity. Um, even talking to him
after games, you know, uh, obviously my,
uh, past couple years playing versus
Detroit when I was in Dallas. Um, you
know, talking to him after the game and
staying in contact with each other. You
know, it's, like I say, it's more than
just football. It's a brotherhood. You
know, obviously talking to him today, at
the end of the day, he has a job to do
and I have a job to do. And it don't
matter about the relationship because at
the end of the day it's a business and I
have to put my best foot forward just
like he have to put his best foot
forward because I have family. He have
family and we want to uh take care of
our kids, take care of our family.
>> You um you enjoyed the honor of wearing
the number 18 at LSU. Um got another one
of those guys in this locker room in Mai
Wingo.
>> Yeah.
>> Um you know what what does that honor
still mean to you? How do you kind of
carry that um that into the league to
this day?
>> Sure. So, I uh my first uh two years in
Dallas, I wore 33. And then when Jaylen
Tober switched to number one, I I told
him, "Hey, bro, if you switch your
number, please let me know." And he told
me, "Hey, I'm switching to number one."
So, I uh I was able to get uh number 18.
But 18 means a lot to me. It's an honor
to be able to represent the number 18
with guys that won it before me. Um, you
know, exemplifies the the standard of
LSU both on and off the field. You know,
that's what I live by. You know, I'm not
going to let a number define me, but I
do know what it means at LSU. That's how
I live my life. You know, I live my life
that way, you know, and like I said, it
was an honor and being able to uh be in
the locker room with Wingo now and he
wore 18 as well, you know. It's an
honor, man. Just like having other LSU
guys in the locker room. It uh it'll
help me, you know, as I get to know the
rest of my team, my uh teammates, and
I'm looking forward to that.
>> Appreciate you. Congratulations.
>> Thank you,
>> Rich.
>> Hey, we saw you last year. You were near
the top of the league in tackles on
special teams. You had a bigger role in
that phase than you ever had before in
your career. What What is it about
special teams or I guess about you that
that you perform well there,
>> man? anything for me to help my team get
the victory. You know, obviously
everybody want to play on defense, but
you know, that comes with your role. You
know, my role last year, it decreased on
the defensive side, but it increased um
on the special team side. And that's
okay. You know, like I say, every
morning I wake up in the morning, I just
thank God for the opportunity. I got
homeboys and people back at the crib
that they'll do anything just to be on
practice squad, you know, something like
that. So you have to make the most of
every opportunity and you got to put
that on the forefront of your mind is
that God's wish to be in this position.
So you know I'm in this position so
don't complain about it. Just put your
head down and go to work. And I mean
that's that was the circumstances. You
know I had to deal with that in Dallas.
Uh really my last two years in Dallas I
dealt with that having an increased role
on special teams and the decreased role
in the defensive snaps. But I'm here
today know the passes in the past. you
know, look forward to whatever I can do
to help this team win because I just
from watching, you know, from afar, this
team has always been a play or two away,
a game away, you know, and I I want to
add to that to already great group of
guys, great group of coaches that they
already have here.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you,
>> Dave.
>> Hey, congrats on uh on signing up here.
Welcome to to Detroit. Um, two things
just to follow up on what Justin asked.
Was was Shep a big reason a big part of
why you signed here? And have you stayed
in contact with him since you left OSU?
>> Oh, I always stay in contact with Shep
regardless of the fact of, you know, him
being the defensive coordinator. He
started out as the outside linebacker
coach, then inside linebacker, now he's
the the D coordinator. It's it's a
relationship. LSU is a brotherhood. Like
it don't matter if you I played at LSU
from 18 to uh 21, but if I meet somebody
that played in 1995 or whatever, like
it's not like a oh, okay, you played at
that time, I played at this time, like
it's it's a brotherhood, you know, LSU
when you purple and gold goes a long
way, you know, and um I keep in touch
with him like obviously like just to
sharpen my game. Like my biggest thing
with me, I always want to get better,
you I don't want to stay the same. And
he tell me when I'm doing good things,
tell me when I'm when I need to work on
things. And it's, you know, that's
that's all part of it, you know. I'm a
I'm a sponge. I want to learn as much as
I can, you know, because I know the
player that I I can be and I know the
player that I want to be. So, for me,
it's all about just like taking the
coaching. Um, when guys telling you
something, they're not just telling you
just to say they just to say they told
you. They telling you because obviously
they want the best for you and they know
what you can do. So, I'm uh blessed just
to be in this uh position to be able to
come here and get coached by Shep, you
know, cuz I I know how he is, you know,
outside of outside of ball and it ain't
no different. He's going to always shoot
it straight to you. And like I
mentioned, it don't matter just because
I've been knowing Shep at the end of the
day. I talked to him today at the end of
the day, I need to do what I got to do.
There's no homeboys in this business.
Like, you need to come in here, put your
head down, and you go to work. and you
know the best man to win.
>> Do you think what what sort of
opportunity do you think you have to
play on defense here? I mean, you can
look at just uh you can look at the
group of linebackers, man. You got to
tip your hat off to Jack Campbell, man.
played all pro at all pro level last
year obviously you know and you seeing
guys you know that Shep has coached and
developed you know like who wouldn't
want that to be them you know who
wouldn't want that to be them just to
get that opportunity to get that
coaching and you go around on Sundays
you out there flying around making plays
you know that that make yourself proud
make your family proud but also make
your coaches proud too because
everything that you going through
throughout the week you translate it
over to the game and that's that's
honestly what it's all
you know, the coaches, they going to do
their part. We have to do our part.
>> And then last thing, uh I don't know if
you were on the field, but do you what
do you remember about that crazy
sequence at the end of the the 2023
game, the two-point play, you know, that
ran three times and skipper reporting is
eligible and you know what's your laugh
and smile? So, yeah. What do you
remember about that?
>> Yeah, that was uh that was pretty crazy
how I remember it. Um,
honestly, I I remember, you know, they
it was Pane and then Skipper. They both
walked up to him. I don't remember what
was being said or anything, but I know
obviously like if they're walking up,
they telling them, "Hey, I'm eligible."
You know, I don't know what was said.
I'm not going to sit here and act like I
know what was said, but all I know at
the time in Dallas, they got the
victory. It was a crazy sequence. It was
that and then it was uh they wound up I
know Micah jumped off sides on one of
them or something. It was it was
something crazy like and this
>> there were three of them three two-point
plays there.
>> Yeah. You can't like you like bro like
it's like boom boom oh boom. So it's
like it was it was real crazy. It was it
was crazy. But then I got to admit the
next year they came back to Dallas and
uh yeah it was
it's pretty crazy. It was it was pretty
crazy. You got guys catching the ball,
tossing it back to Paneet like he
running. They lining up at receiver on
us. Uh actually one of the plays that
game I think he wound up reporting
eligible again and this time we was on
it this time and me I wound up breaking
the pass up but also they did a run fake
so I stepped down
>> and then I turned around. I'm like oh.
And I turn around just start running. So
I I remember that play. But yeah, that
was a a crazy sequence of events and
just obviously like playing against the
Lions like you need to be prepared
because those guys going to be physical
and they they go in the house marching.
>> You you broke a pass up that was
intended for skipper or one lineman that
game.
>> Uh I think it was uh not Skipper, it was
uh was 68 Decker.
>> Decker. Decker. Okay.
>> It was Decker. It was uh I remember they
had all white on. We had on uh navy blue
jerseys. Yeah. Do that very first one,
were you confused as to who I mean, did
they pull one over on you guys that like
you guys didn't know who was eligible?
>> Come out uh two years ago or two.
>> Not the one that had the crazy sequence.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm be honest with you. I
>> look I just know like I saw two people
standing over there with the with the
ref. So I don't know what was being said
or what not. I just like hey like it was
on our side that day. We won. That's all
I know. We won the game. It was it was a
crazy sequence of events, but we won the
game.
>> Good to be on this side of it now where
you don't have to worry about some of
that, you know, craziness going on.
>> Well, you got to know like it's a
copycat league, so like everybody going
to do it. You know what I'm saying? You
got to you got to be just be prepared
for it and have your antennas up.
>> Awesome. Hey, congratulations again.
Appreciate it.
>> Thank you all. Thank you.
>> Will, last one.
>> Real quick, just to clarify, is it
Demone or Damon?
>> Uh, Deone.
>> Deone. Okay. Hey, so uh at the end of
2023, they all thought they were going
to see you guys again in the playoffs.
Did you guys think you would collide for
a second time after that kind of
controversial ending in in in uh
December?
>> I knew like at after the game it was
like a All right, we see you guys later.
Like y'all got this one, but we'll see
y'all to get in the playoffs. So I I
pretty much thought that we work on the
play. I don't remember what happened. Um
Oh, we played Green Bay. I think that's
when we played. Yeah, we played Greeny
Bay.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So,
>> yeah, you played them.
>> Yeah. Yeah. We We played Green Bay and,
you know, was not luck that day, but I I
for sure thought that we were going to
uh I for sure thought that we was going
to play in the playoffs again.
>> And then, um, when you think back to
your first two seasons when you were
playing a lot defensively and in 2023,
led your team in tackles, when when you
were, um, playing, I guess, just sort of
the peak of of your defensive abilities
in the NFL, what do you feel like was
driving that? Um, what are your best
attributes when when your game is at
your best? I
>> I think it it all boils down to having
coaches that believe in you. You know,
coaches that's going to coach you the
way that you want to be coached, coaches
that are willing, you know, and all
those things that I described describe
coach Ham and describe Coach Shep here,
you know, it's it's all about like the
I'm a relationship guy, you know. I'm
the type of person that you can coach
me, you can coach me hard, be real with
me. Like I I love coaches that you you
have more respect for guys that be real
with you. You know what I'm saying? Even
like when I was playing, I honestly just
going out there just playing ball, you
know? Like now I want to get to the
point to where it's like, you know, you
understand ball. You're not just going
out there playing seatball get ball cuz
that can take you a long way both good
and like it could not be so good when
you out there just playing seat ball get
ball. So you know just my coaching style
the way just just be real, be upfront.
be hard on me because I'm I'm hard on
myself. So like that's the biggest thing
with me. I'm my own biggest critic and I
want to be just as great as the coaches
want me to be. But ultimately it boils
down to me, my preparation and how I
prepare myself. And you know, I can't
get uh can't wait to get here with the
guys, get with Coach Ham and get with
Coach Shep and know the guys and really
just learn, just start over from scratch
and you know, just be a sponge.
>> Thank you, Don. I appreciate it. Thank
y'all.